

UGUR BOZKAYA

SALES & BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER



Profile

I am a dedicated, well-organized and methodical individual with experiences of multicultural work environment. Ι have aood interpersonal skills, am an excellent humanitarian, team worker. I am very willing to learn, develop new skills. I am reliable and dependable. I have an active and dynamic approach to work and getting things done. I am determined and decisive.



Contact

Road 5704, Block 257 Floating City, Amwaj Islands Kingdom of Bahrain



+973 34646919 bozkayaugur@hotmail.com Skype: bzkya.ugur

DoB: 08.09.1989 Nationality: Turkish Driving License: Bahrain/Turkey



Education

Master's in 2017 International cancelled
Relations due to
Ahmet Yesevi relocate to
University, Bahrain
Kazakhstan

Bachelor's in 2008 2015 International Relations Cukurova University, Turkey

Mehmet Uygun High 2003 2006 School



Work Experience

Sales & Business Development Manager ODADECOR, RIFFA/BAHRAIN

April 2018-Present

<u>Strategic planning -</u> to analyze trends and results, determine annual unit and gross-profit plans by implementing sales marketing strategies, design/implement a strategic business, promote marketing campaigns, promotions and execute them in a structured way; analyze, foresee, and understand potential buyer needs

<u>Store Management - product pricing, promotion planning, purchasing, inventory, cost & stock controlling, to supervise, coach and motivate the sales force to develop their skills, well-prepared stores for promotions, meetings etc.</u>

<u>Brand Management -</u> to create company's own brand policies, maintain the unit as per the brand standards, manage market position and customer expectations, develop specific products that satisfy customer needs

<u>Business Development -</u> to develop a growth strategy, conduct research to identify new markets, arrange business meetings, promote the company's products/services, provide trustworthy feedback and after-sales support, build long-term relationships with new and existing customers, develop entry level staff into valuable salespeople, social media management

<u>Sales & Marketing</u> - to establish sales objectives by forecasting and developing annual sales quotas for region; project expected sales volume and profit for existing/new products, plan to ensure achievement of divisional/personal target

Wholesale - to create own wholesale policy and pricing, manage accounts & teams, develop growth strategies, attending meeting to present the company, analyze sales, create/implement/execute merchandising plans, analyzing/attending important global events and trade shows to improve product quality and creativity

Chief Finance Officer Association for Aid and Relief Japan, HQ, SANLIURFA/TURKEY Dec 2016-Apr 2018

<u>Auditing -</u> completeness and preparation of audits with UNHCR, BPRM, Japan Government, Undersecretariat of Treasury of Turkey (for 12 million \$ per year)

<u>Finance Management -</u> supervise and train all local Finance officers in all projects for 4 cities(Istanbul, Sanliurfa, Mardin, Gaziantep), project program process of HQ Turkey, leading the preparation of all financial operations, audits, budget,

expenditure, preparation of project budget plan

Reporting - Preparation of financial program reports both internal and external, financial project reports both monthly and annual, donor's activities report to HQ

Financial Accounting - monthly payroll preparation, payment of salaries for all offices, preparation of TAX and Social Security and its related payments, and

maintain all bank accounts related documents in all offices, ensure integrity of

accounts and promote accurate and timely accounting

<u>Closely work with</u> - Finance Department at HQ in Japan, to implement the AAR Japan-wide Finance policies and advice on improving policies, dealing with contacted lawyer, banks and accountants, Headquarter Office, Head of Office of Turkey and Country Director, all finance officers, procurement & HR departments

General Manager MT GROUP, MANAMA/BAHRAIN August 2015-July 2016

<u>Sales Management -</u> to train, coach & control store supervisors, import and export, analyze trends and results for standards, order as company requirements & customer needs, represent brand & company in business platforms

<u>Stores Management</u> — to operate five retail well-known brands' stores and one wholesales store management, team, time & budget management, sales income & development reporting, visual designing, promotions, all daily operations, stock & inventory controlling, coordinate supervisors for sales target

<u>Business Development - planning</u>, monitoring and reinforcing performance standards, strategize and plan the sales process management, forecasting, pricing, key account management, expenses, profitability, new product development, market research and brand strategy, Making agreements the companies to collaborate with and seeking new markets in middle east, brand management and advertisement, improving sales and targets, conduct meetings

Languages _

- ✓ Turkish Native
- ✓ English Fluent

Skills -

- √ Business Development
- ✓ Strategic Planning
- √ Start-up Growth Strategy
- ✓ Sales/Marketing Management
- ✓ Auditing & Accounting
- ✓ Brand Management
- ✓ Internal/External Reporting
- ✓ Strategic Relationship Building
- √ POS System
- ✓ RMAN
- √ Store(s) Management
- √ Stock/Inventory Management
- ✓ Excel, Word, PowerPoint
- Leadership
- ✓ Crisis Management
- ✓ No travel restriction
- / Desire for lifelong learning

Membership _

- ✓ Turkey Youth Association
- Community Volunteers
 Foundation
- ✓ Habitat Center for Governance & Development
- ✓ Youth Entrepreneurs Group
- ✓ Turkey National Youth Council
- ✓ Adana City Council
- ✓ Mersin City Council
- ✓ IM Literature Workshop
- ✓ Fine Art Academy of Cukurova University

Sales & Marketing Supervisor Gano Excel International, ADANA/TURKEY

<u>Sales & Marketing</u>—to strategize sales & marketing plans, advertise company products, brand products for food & beverage & health, commercialize network-marketing system, improve client portfolio & create potential client portfolio, enhance budget, market search, supervise & train the team, develop skills for Salesforce in the field, motivate the team to increase their portfolio and sales targets monthly, follow their commission based sales, educate them for strong product knowledge, report client, sales, portfolio and marketing process.

Property and Investment Analyst Koridoor Real Estate & Investment Consulting, ADANA/TURKEY Sep 2012 - Jun 2013

<u>Property Analyze-</u> to research trends and statistics in the real estate market, provide financial analysis in support to the financing, acquisition, marketing and leasing of a certain property, manage company's real estate investment portfolio, involve evaluating his client's credit, helping negotiate lease, monitor and analyze specified commercial and residential real estate market conditions

<u>Investment Analyze</u> to screen potential investment opportunities, analyze construction processes, play a key role in quarterly reporting, variance monitoring, maintain and improve internal tracking worksheets and databases, supervise market research advisors in procuring and analyzing market rates and expenses, actively participate in high-level presentations for clients

Child Space Activity Supervisor Sato Seyhan, ADANA/TURKEY

Apr 2010 - Jul 2012

Activity Management - to guide and coach primarily in activity, plan & supervise during activities, modify activities to suit the needs of specific groups (between 3 to 10 ages), organize and lead the plan for child and group activities, lead and coach the team, children & group for activities in person

<u>Space Management -</u> to organize and set up the equipment for recreational activity, ensure beneficial use of activity tools and place, keep tools and plan

Certificates / Seminars / Conferences _

- \checkmark Training of Management organized by Main Office of Association for Aid and Relief Japan, 2018
- ✓ First Aid Training organized by Turkish Red Crescent, 2017
- ✓ Middle East Winter School Seminar organized by Centre for Middle Eastern Strategic Studies, 2015
- ✓ European Union Workshop organized by TANDEM & Conrad Adeneur Shiftung, 2014
- ✓ European Youth Forum organized by European Union Turkey Delegation, 2014
- Economic Relationship Between Turkey and European Union Afterwards Arab Spring organized by Cukurova University, 2013
- ✓ Third Turkey Economic Conference organized by Turkey Youth Council & Young Entrepreneurs Group, 2011
- ✓ Globalization Workshop organized by Cag University, 2011
- √ Fourth Young Entrepreneurs and Leaders Seminar organized by Modern Academy Club, 2011
- ✓ Education of Computer Educator organized by Microsoft & United Nations Development Program, 2010
- ✓ Conference for "Direct Your Future" organized by TTNET & Personal Development Academy, 2010
- \checkmark Globalization and Free Market Economy organized by Friedrich Naumann Shiftung, 2009

References_

- ❖ Tugce Bozkaya SME Expert Advisor, Banque Cantonale de Genève(BCGE) Switzerland tugce.bozkaya@bcge.ch / +41 78 850 29 59
- Wolfgang Haagen 'Former' German Deputy Ambassador in Bahrain Germany whaagen@yahoo.com / +49 176 23356301
- Khalil M. Othman Head of Office, Association for Aid and Relief Japan Turkey_ khalil.osman@aarturkey.org / +90 537 951 10 34
- Sawako Sakagami Finance Coordinator, Association for Aid and Relief Japan HQ Japan_sawako.sakagami@qmail.com / +81 90 6148 6337